I think this development has to be a sign that Biribiri's going to be the heroine!
この展開はビリビリ ヒロイン化の兆しだと思うんっすよね～！
You're...
君は…
Help me!
助けて！
Are you telling me you'd separate it from its body for your own sake?
一人の人間として生きているらしい首をどうしようっていうの？
I have to see her, no matter what!
私はどうしてもあの子に会いたい
They're probably from Yagiri Pharmaceuticals.
あれは たぶん 「矢霧製薬」の連中だな
It's okay. Leave everything to your sister.
いいのよ 全部 姉さんに任せて
Honestly, I half-assumed he was.
正直 疑い半分だったんだが
This evening, the ball's in my court.
駒は私の手の内にあります
I have to go.
行かなくちゃ… 彼女を取り戻しに行かなくちゃ
I have to go get her back.
My sister can't do it.
姉さんなんかじゃダメだ オレじゃなきゃ…
It has to be...
It has to be me.
オレじゃなきゃダメなんだ
She wasn't there?
いなかったですって!?
Yes.
はい
The underlings said that she'd already left by the time they arrived.
下の連中が行ったときには すでに女はいなかったそうです
You said the student who rents that room is Ryugamine, didn't you?
その部屋の学生… 竜ヶ峰といったわよね？
What about him?
そいつは？
They asked him some questions when he returned, and
they were going to bring him back should it come to that...
戻ってきたときに話を聞き
どうも連れがいたらしく…
However, it seemed he had some friends with him...
その連れごと来てもらえば
His friends should have just come as well.
よかったでしょ
You're useless.
使えないわね
What shall we do?
いかがいたしましょう？
Hello?
もしもし
Is this Ms. Yagiri Namie?
矢霧波江さんですか？
Who might you be?
どちらさまですか？
My name is...Ryugamine Mikado.
私は竜ヶ峰帝人といいます
Shall we make a deal?
取り引きをしませんか？
I'm hungry.
My...
Welcome, welcome!
イラッシャ～イ イラッシャ～イ
Russian sushi?
「ロシアズシ」 うまいヨ～ 安いヨ～！
It's good.
It's cheap!
"What is life?"
「人生ってなんだ？」
Hi, mister.
Are you hungry?
"What do people live for?"
「人はなんのために生きている？」
We have some good ingredients today.
Or so someone asked me, and I beat him to within an inch of his life.
そう問いかけられて オレはそいつを死ぬ寸前まで殴ってやったわけよ
Oh yeah, it won't make you sick.
I see.
そうダネ～
It might be different if he were some middle school dreamer,
but it should be a crime for an adult yakuza to say that, right?
ポエマーな中学生ならともかく
二十歳過ぎたヤクザが言うのは犯罪だろう？
I see.
そうダネ～
Hey, Simon...you don't get what I'm saying, do you?
っていうかサイモンさんよぉ
オレの話 よく分かってねぇだろ？
Yeah, you're right.
んん～ そうダネ～
Have I changed?
私は変わってしまったのだろうか？
I've lived in this town...
２０年間 この街で暮らして…
For twenty years...
They haven't been in vain.
無駄なんかじゃないさ
Those twenty years you've lived here haven't been in vain.
君が生きてきた２０年は無駄なんかじゃない
Nothing will be in vain as long as you
make use of them during the rest of your life.
これからの人生に生かせれば
どんなことだって無駄じゃないさ
Make use of them?
生かす？ 一体何に生かせというんだ!?
How am I supposed to do that?!
For example...
例えば…
You could marry me.
僕と結婚すればいい
Shinra...
新羅…
Are you Mikado?
あなたが帝人君？
You look much more docile than I'd imagined.
想像していたよりずっとおとなしそうな子ね
Or maybe that's the kind of kid you have to look out for these days?
それとも 今はこういう子が危ないのかしら？
Anyway, what's this deal you mentioned?
それで 取り引きって何かしら？
I have the person you've been looking for.
私はあなたの捜している人を預かっています
I see.
そう いくら欲しいの？
How much do you want?
I don't need any money.
いえ お金はいりません
Then what do you want?
じゃあ 何がお望み？
The truth.
真実です
What did you just say?
今 なんて言ったのかしら？
I want you to admit what your brother did to Harima Mika...
あなたの弟が張間美香さんにやったこと
...and what you two did to her body.
そして あなたたちが美香さんの体にやったことを認めてもらいたいんです
Sadly enough, I only have circumstantial evidence...
残念なことに 状況証拠しかないので
So I'll be straight with you.
率直に言います 自首してください
Turn yourself in.
I see. That's the type of person you are.
そう あなた そういう人なのね
Hm?
I won't forgive anyone who gets in the way of my brother.
許せない 弟の邪魔をするなんて
I won't have it!
いけないのよ…
Anyone who gets in my brother's way...shouldn't exist.
弟の邪魔をする人はいたら いけないのよ！
I see.
そうか この人はこういう人か
That's how...this person is.
Hey, tell me.
ねえ 教えてよ 姉さんはどこ？
Where's my sister?
I have to go.
行かなきゃいけないんだよ 彼女にはオレが必要なんだ
The girl needs me.
I have to be with her!
オレがいなきゃいけないんだ
Hey, tell me!
ねえ 教えてくれよ！
That's the reason?
そんな理由か…
That's the reason someone had to
die and have her body used that way?!
そんな理由で 人が死んで
その体を使って あんなことをして…
They're even targeting me...!
僕のことまで狙って…
That's the reason you killed someone?
そんな理由で人の命を？
Are you trying to make Yagiri
miserable with your complacence?!
あなたの自己満足で 矢霧君を不幸にさせるつもりなんですか？
What're you saying?
今更 何 言ってんの？
If that's all you can say after growing up and stepping out into this world, then shut that unpleasant mouth of yours.
その年になって こんな世界に足を突っ込んで…
It's okay.
大丈夫だよね？
その不快な口を閉じなさい
I may be sugar-coating things...
確かにきれい事かもしれません
But so what if I am?!
だから なんだっていうんですか？
Aren't you the one who can't understand
that you should repent for killing someone?!
人を殺した反省をしろっていう
今更以前のことも理解できないのはそっちじゃないですか!?
You watch too many dramas.
ドラマの見すぎよ
Those are just promises and Leibniz's
pre-established harmony; we live in reality.
お約束な予定調和ばかり ここは現実なのよ？
This'll work, right?
This isn't some epic poem.
うまくいくよね？
You're no hero, either.
あなたは英雄なんかでもない 身の程を知りなさい！
Know your place!
What's so bad about all that?!
それの 何が悪いっていうんですか！
Pre-established harmony, promises, and opportunism?!
予定調和も お約束も ご都合主義も
I love forced happy endings!
無理やりのハッピーエンドだって 大好きですよ！
What's so bad about wanting to have one?!
それを目指して 何が悪いっていうんですか！
I won't say it's for the sake of humanity or the world...
人のためだとか 世界のためだとか そんなことは言いません
I just want to see one!
ただ 僕が見たいんです！ 僕が信じたいんです！
I want to believe in them!
That's right. I believe.
そうだ 信じる 僕は信じる
I believe!
That everyone...definitely will...
みんな きっと…
It may be a trite idea...
確かに こんなのありふれた考えかもしれません
But the fact that it's trite means
everybody's thinking about it that much!
でも ありふれてるっていうことは
それだけみんながそのことを考えてるってことなんです！
Is that all you wanted to say?
言いたいことは それだけ？
I have neither the power nor the knowledge to
challenge someone who doesn't understand reason.
理屈の通じない相手に
挑む力も 知恵も 僕にはありません
I don't even have the time to try.
努力する時間さえも与えてもらえない
That's why...
だから！
I'm relying on numbers!
僕は 数に頼る！
What?!
何っ!?
That's amazing!
すっげぇ～！ これ全部そうなんっすかねぇ？
They're all part of this, right?
It's awesome!
すっご～い！ なんだか まるで「Missing」の怪奇現象じゃん！
It's like one of the paranormal phenomena in "Missing!"
坊ちゃん メールでございます
Sir, you have mail. Sir, you have mail.
Would you like to try dying once?
いっぺん 死んでみる？
We got it!
来た～！
Are you serious?
ジかよ
Well then...
さてと
Togusa, I'm counting on you.
渡草 あとは頼んだぞ
Yeah.
Let's do this.
行くぞ
Just how many of them are there?
一体何人いるんだろう？
Wow, I can't believe this many
people showed up for our first gathering!
いやいやいや 初集会でここまで集まるなんて
驚きっすねぇ～
These are...
これが… ダラーズ？
The Dollars?!
Hey, Isaac!
ねえ アイザック～！
What is it, Miria?
なんだ～い？ ミリア
Are these people also part of The Dollars?
この人たちもダラーズってのの 一員なの？
Yeah, that's right, Miria!
ああ そのとおりだ ミリア
Alright now, listen up.
いいか～？ よく聞け
We're part of the most "now," the youngest, and the most talked-about—
これで オレたちも 巷で今いちばん ナウなヤングに超話題の…
What is this?
何これ？ まさか こいつら全員？
They couldn't all be...?!
No way. No way!
Look! It's a franchise!
うそ… うそ～！
But we've only just met!
なんと！ 今日初めて出会ったばっかりなのに!?
Amazing!
すっご～い！ すっご～い！すっご～い…
The sky over my hometown was clear and vast.
地元の空は高くて広かった
But...
でも…何もなかった
It was also empty.
When I was a kid, this town was filled with adventure.
子供のころはこの町も冒険にあふれていた
いつからだろう？ こんなふうになってしまったのは
When did it all change?
I wanted to change something.
何かを変えたかった
But I had neither the will nor a reason to leave.
でも 飛び出す理由も勇気もなかった
That's when it happened.
そんなときだった…
Twice...twice...
えっと～ ２回… ２回
Various worlds unfolded for me there.
そこにはいろんな世界が広がっていた
Worlds that I didn't know and couldn't reach...
僕の知らない 僕が届かない世界
I was able to talk with Kida again, even though he'd moved to Tokyo.
東京に引っ越した紀田君とまたやり取りもするようになった
I made new friends as well.
新しい知り合いもできた
One day, I suddenly thought of something.
あるとき ふと思いついた
At first, it was only a simple joke.
最初は単なるネタに過ぎなかった
A group?
チーム？
Yeah.
そう
I heard there are a bunch of different groups in Tokyo.
You mean make a group on the Internet?
No, we'd actually...make one in real life.
It'd be based in Ikebukuro and we'd spread rumors about it online.
We wouldn't tell people we were in The Dollars.
自分たちがダラーズのメンバーだとは 名乗らない
We'd just say we heard about them from
someone else, and get our name out that way.
いかにもよそから聞いたというふうに噂話を流し
名前を広める
I even made a group site.
チームのサイトも作ってみた
It was secured by a password.
完全パスワード制
We leaked the password via email and different message boards.
パスワードはメールやいろんな掲示板を使って流した
We fabricated a lot of member posts on message boards, too.
掲示板にメンバーの書き込みも大量に用意した
Of course, there were lots of people who didn't believe us.
もちろん信用しない人も多かった
But then, others started standing up for us...
そのうち 擁護する人たちも現れて
And everyone was happy.
みんな 大喜びだった
Seriously?!
Everyone believes it!
These people are idiots!
I did have a bad feeling about this.
嫌な予感はしていた…
People in real life started calling themselves Dollars.
現実の世界にダラーズを名乗る人たちが現れはじめた
That wasn't all.
それだけじゃない
The number of members kept increasing while we weren't paying attention.
知らないうちにメンバーも増殖を続けていた
Even though we'd stopped giving out the password...
もう パスワードを流すことはやめていたのに
It was like someone somewhere...
まるで どこかで 誰かが情報を流しているように…
Was giving out the information.
Is everyone watching?
Heeeey!
They may have gotten scared...
怖くなったのか
But the people I created The Dollars with disappeared.
一緒にダラーズをつくったみんなはいなくなってしまった
Yet I didn't quit.
僕はそれでもやめなかった
No, I couldn't quit.
いや やめられなかったんだ
Even I don't know why, but...
なぜだか自分でも分からない
けど…
That's not true.
There may be some bad people here.
However, there should be tons of people who aren't.
All we have to do is make
The Dollars into a good group, right?
僕らでダラーズを良い集団にすればいいんじゃないでしょうか？
We could do things that will get rid of our bad reputation.
悪い事をしている人達の印象を消せるくらい良い事をするとか？
Like pick up trash around town or erase graffiti...
例えば 街のゴミを拾うとか 壁の落書きを消すとか…
And so, the residents are quite perplexed.
ということで 住民も大変不思議がっております
The graffiti on this wall was definitely here yesterday...
こちらにあった壁の落書き
昨日の深夜までは確かにあったそうなのですが
As you can see, it is now completely gone.
このようにきれいに消えてしまいました
It seems unlikely that one person could have erased...
大がかりな落書きだけに
一人で消したとは とても思えず
...this graffiti that took many people to paint it...
近隣住民も困惑している状態に…
It couldn't be...
まさかね…
I left for Tokyo on Kida's invitation.
紀田君に誘われて 東京に出てきた
And there...
そこで…
The Dollars?
ダラーズ？
I don't know much about them, either.
オレも詳しいことは分かんねぇんだけどよ
Anyway, it seems there are lots of them and they all have short tempers.
とにかく人数が多くて 線が一本ぶち切れたチームらしい
They're apparently a gang, but no one knows what color they are.
カラーギャングらしいんだけど どんな色なのかも分からねぇ
Don't approach them just out of curiosity.
興味本位で近づかない方がいい
Don't be unnecessarily inquisitive.
余計な詮索はよしておくことだな
But the strongest people in town now are The Dollars, right?
でも 今この街最強ったらダラーズでしょ？
So, what kind of group are these Dollars?
で ダラーズってさ どんなチーム？
If I had to say, I guess they're "clearly colorless."
あえて言うと 無色透明って感じかな
The Dollars? I know them.
ダラーズ？ 知ってるぜ
Because I am one.
っていうか オレ ダラーズ
I got a girlfriend by joining The Dollars!
ダラーズに入って 彼女ができました！
They write stupid stuff on message boards—
くだらないことを掲示板に書き込んだり…
Someone always replies to your posts.
誰かがなんかレスしてくれるし
At this age, you can't form relationships with anybody outside of work.
この年になると 仕事以外の人間関係なんて出来ないしねぇ
Have you heard? The Dollars saved some people from human traffickers!
知ってるか!? 例の人間狩りにさらわれそうになったヤツを
ダラーズが助けたんだってよ！
The Dollars are the strongest!
ダラーズ 最高～！
Not really. It's fun; isn't that enough?
別に… 楽しいし いいんじゃない？
This is much more fun than I thought it'd be.
思った以上だ 楽しいよ
This is fun, isn't it?
楽しいよねぇ
What?
何っ!? なんなの？
What's going on?
Who are these people?!
こいつら なんなのよ！
Hey, where do you think The Dollars' founder is from?
ねえねえ ダラーズの創始者ってどの人だろう？
Is there an Arabian oil tycoon here?
アラブの石油王っぽい人いる～？
Doesn't look like it.
いないっすねぇ
The person who sent us that response
is the true founder of The Dollars, right?
渡草さん オレたちにレスくれたのって 本物の創始者なんっすよねぇ？
Uhh...or so I've heard...
って話だが…
Togusa, the light's red!
渡草！ 信号 赤 赤！ 赤～?
It's red! It's red!
The quiet type, huh?
だんまりかよ
Dotachin, Dotachin!
ドタチン ドタチン！
I told you not to call me that.
だから その名前で…
Someone responded to my post on The Dollars' message board.
これ！ ダラーズの掲示板にレス来た！
Everything's in order.
手はずは整いました
I'll let you meet her.
彼女と会わせます
In return, I'd like for you to cooperate with me as well.
そのかわり あなたも私に協力してください
Celty.
セルティ
He's not here.
いない…
What're you spacing out for?!
何をぼやぼやしているの！ さっさと捜しなさい！
Start looking for him!
Yes, ma'am. Move it!
はい！
どけ！
Where'd he go?
どこに行った！
Shit. Move it!
くそっ！ どけ！
どこだ!?
Out of my way.
I've had it!
Who said that?
誰の声？
I have no head!
私には首がない！ 私は化け物だ！
I'm a monster!
I don't have a mouth with which to talk, or even
eyes with which to communicate my passion to others!
多くを語る口も 相手に情熱を伝える瞳も 持たない！
Do you hear something?
何か聞こえる
Where's it coming from?
なんの声だ？
So what if I don't?!
だが それがどうした！ それがどうしたというのだ！
Celty...
セルティ…
I'm right here.
私はここにいる 確かにここに存在する
I definitely exist here.
Who the hell are you?!
なんだ てめぇは!?
You're—
Since I have no eyes, I'll show you all what I really am!
目がないというのなら
我が行状のすべてを刮目して見るがいい！
Die!
でやぁ～！
Listen as much as you want to the
screams of those who've seen a monster!
化け物の怒りに触れた者の叫びを 存分に耳にするといい！
The...the headless rider...
く… 首なしライダー…
The headless rider.
首なしライダー！
Who?
あれが… 首なしライダー!?
The headless rider?
I'm here.
私はここだ ここにいる… ここにいるのだ
I'm right here.
I'm right here!
I'm already crying out...crying out that...!
私はすでに叫んでる… 叫んでいるぞ！
"I've been born right here and now!"
私は 今 ここに生まれた！
All so my existence can be etched upon this city!
私の存在をこの街に刻みつけるために！
So you're Ryugamine Mikado?
お前が竜ヶ峰帝人か？
Celty...
セルティを… セルティを返せ～?
Give Celty back to me!
That's right.
制作：lastzzz 安静の云 akira アキラ
そう 私はこの街で一つの真実を発見した
I found out a single truth in this town.
I'd been looking for something too common, too easy to find.
あまりにもあっけなく あまりにもありふれたものを探し当てた
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs/
That boy will probably once again...
たぶん あの少年も また…
Next Time: Everything's Relative.